WALTER CLAYTON



Phone Number: +32476013223

Email: walter.h.clayton@gmail.com

Portfolio: www.walterclayton.com

Location: Brussels, Belgium

Hard skills: Frontend, Figma, CSS, HTML, Typescript, React, WordPress **Soft skills:** Creativity, Empathy, Problem Solving, Communication, Team Work

"Simplicity is complexity resolved" - Brancusi

PROFILE

Frontend web designer and developer with more than 4 years of experience and a passion for making products intuitive and beautiful. Able to translate abstract ideas into visual web components with design and code tools. Developed a somatotype web app, a nation ranking Ecommerce website, and contributed to European Institutional websites and an asset management web app. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations, and databases. Always keeps up to date of latest technologies and innovations. Experienced team leader, player and independent worker, who likes to achieve and deliver. Enjoys working with people who ask strong questions, have visual taste and logic, a clear vision, an entrepreneurial mindset, and communicates short, sweet, and concisely.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer, Brussels, Belgium — August 2021 - Present www.walterclavton.com

- Built with EJS and Bootstrap
- Designed with Figma
- Currently migrating to WordPress and Frontity (React)

www.afitpilot.com

Key responsibilities for the website:

- Author and content creator
- Designed all pages and avatars (Figma, Affinity Publisher, React, Typescript, and MUI)
- Managed a team of 3 developers (2 frontend and 1 backend) using Agile methodology
- Designed Backend Architecture

Key achievement for the website:

- Finished the MVP in 2 months

www.leagueofnations.co.uk

Key responsibilities for the website:

- Designed and created algorithm (Google Sheets) and website (WordPress, Elementor, and MailChimp)
- Implemented funnel strategies for user conversions (landing, freebie, and paid content pages)

Key achievement for the website:

- Fully functional, members get access to exclusive content
- Provided full documentation for the client to manage the CMS and algorithm (Videos and Google Docs)

Solution Analyst, NTT DATA, Brussels, Belgium — September 2021 - September 2022

Key responsibilities:

- Conducting remote functional workshops with key stakeholders (Microsoft Teams)
- Writing functional documents after requirements gathering (Word and Excel)
- Designing Use Case Graphs (Figma)
- Collaborating with UX/UI designers, Information Architects, Drupal Developers, and clients to agree upon website features (Microsoft Teams)

Key projects:

Projects included migrating the <u>European Research Council (ERC)</u>, the <u>European Securities and Markets Authority (ESMA)</u>, and the <u>European Banking Authority (EBA)</u> from old Drupal to new Drupal versions, and gathering the requirements for creating the European Cybersecurity Collaboration Platform.

Lead Frontend Web Developer, Finlight, London — April 2020 - August 2021 www.finlight.com

Key responsibilities for the website:

- Completed full redesign of existing website to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings (Figma, Bulma and Flask)
- Collaborated with marketing department to determine organisational need and design pages (Hubspot)
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity, and SEO

Key responsibilities for the web app:

- Designed intuitive graphical user interfaces (Figma)
- Created SPAs (Vue.js, Buefy, and Django)

Key achievements:

- 2 Step Authentication (Firebase)
- Onboarding tour (Vue.js)
- SEO, accessibility, best practices and performance above 90% (Chrome Inspector and Lighthouse)

Web Developer, BeCode, Brussels — June 2019 - April 2020

Key responsibilities:

- Developed prototype full-stack web applications such as YelpCamp and Getflix (MERN, and LAMP)
- Working in small groups of 4-5 developers.

Web Developer Intern, TechMex, London — December 2018 - June 2019

Key responsibility:

- Studied basic project requirements with technical lead and developed user interfaces (Javascript, HTML5 and CSS3)

CrossFit, Rugby and Powerlifting Coach, CrossFit Capacitas, Brighton — 2017 - 2019

Key responsibility:

- Conducting CrossFit classes and making sure all members move safely
- Coaching off-season strength and conditioning sessions for rugby players

Key achievement:

- Athlete came 2nd at the BPU World Championships
- Athlete turned from amateur to professional rugby player

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Excellent in the **frontend**, making visually attractive designs, interactive, responsive, and user friendly. **Sufficiency** in the backend, good understanding of project structure, MVC, ORM, and database design. **Competent** with version control systems and basic know-how of testing, deployment and hosting.

Frontend: Figma, React, Typescript, Vue.js, Bootstrap5, MUI, Axios, HTML5, Three.js, Chart.js, CSS3,

SCSS, Webpack, Affinity Publisher, Adobe Photoshop, Flourish, ES6, Elementor

Backend: Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, SQlite, Django, Flask

Devops: Heroku, Godaddy, Render, Vercel, WPengine

Operating Systems: Mac **CMS:** Wordpress and Drupal

Unit Testing: Jest

Integration Testing: Postman

Other: VS Code, Git, Docker, Github, MailChimp, Stripe

Web Standards: SEO, Information Architecture, GDPR, Usability, and Speed Performance.

Methodologies: Remote work, Waterfall and Agile

LANGUAGES

French: Fluent English: Fluent

Dutch: B1 level (intermediate) **Spanish:** A2 level (beginner)

EDUCATION

Udemy — Completed courses such as Web Developer Bootcamp, Information Architecture, Business Analyst, Business Models, and Project Management 2019-2023

BeCode — Web Developer Bootcamp, (9 months) 2019-2020

OpenClassroom — Completed courses on Flask, LAMP, and Lean Start-up, 2019

University of Brighton — First Class Honours Bsc(Hons) Sport and Exercise Science, 2014-2017

LEISURE AND RECENT ACTIVITIES

Hackathons: IBM and Telenet Hackathon.

Latest Meetup: NFT: Legal Developments Around the Globe

Currently Reading: Steve Jobs and The Network State

Podcast: Listen weekly to TechTent and Tim Ferris

Entertainment: Salsa, CrossFit

Full Driving License: B

Nationality: British and Belgian